SAI KUSHAAL KATHIRAVAN

D.No.406 Akshaya January, Kelambakkam, Ch-603103 · +91-9003187630

Email ID: saikrishtt2726@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sai-kushaal-kathiravan-a43191a1 Personal Blog: powerofsubconsciousmindblog.wordpress.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

An excellent academic record, ability to understand and test software. A strong understanding in the field of stakeholder management & technologies. I seek to work as a Senior Software Test Engineer/Module Lead to further my knowledge in the IT domain and utilize my skills.

SUMMARY

Sai Kushaal is an EPGP-FSIA graduate, CSM & ISTQB Certified Testing professional with 11 months experience in IT and Banking with an emphasis on Software Testing. Specialized in Client Onboarding modules such as KYC, Customer Due Diligence and Customer Profile Maintenance across interfaces. Had worked under different markets such as India, Singapore and Malaysia in a two-year span and is quick to adapt and understand the business opportunities at program level of different regions.

EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2017 – PRESENT SENIOR TEST ENGINEER, MAVERIC SYSTEMS PVT. LTD.

- Transition from LIBA Intern to Senior Test Engineer happened during this phase.
- Was promoted to the role of Senior Test Engineer on 1st Aug 2018.
- Joined hands with Standard Chartered Bank Global Business Services since 14th November 2017 as LIBA Intern.
- Played a significant role in delivering test execution and test design related software testing artefacts in Real Time Onboarding program which is a Standard Chartered Banking application which is an effort to enhance their client on- boarding experience in the retail banking sector.
- Was highly involved in effective business and project facing stakeholder management which is a critical component to the successful delivery of any project.
- Had worked for multiple markets such as India, Singapore and Malaysia under the same program: Gaining knowledge in the domain of CDD, KYC and Credit Initiation, Customer Onboarding and Customer Profile Maintenance in the retail banking sector.
- RTOB being a transformation program from paper-based process to digital based processes: Had opened the opportunity to work with different Channel based applications such as processing Leads, Tele sales, RM facing digital applications, Customer digital facing applications etc.

- Enroute grew up to become the subject matter expert in the software testing vertical for Real Time Customer Onboarding and the other interfaces that effectively involved internet banking, credit card management system, retail loan management system, customer due diligence, transaction maintenance interfaces.
- Effectively representing business facing software testing which includes User Acceptance Testing, User Verification testing, Production Test Support.
- Effectively used subject matter expertise to bring in suggestions to automate the entire RTOB program for the India & Singapore Markets which was enroute automated successfully by our peer team.

JULY 2017 – OCTOBER 2017 LIBA INTERN, MAVERIC SYSTEMS PVT.LTD.

- Was effectively involved in test designing phase of ZAIN KSA Transformation Engagement.

Writing (Manual Testing) test cases/scripts for modules such as:

- Order Management and Order Care.
- Subscriber Management.
- Partner Relationship Management.

Activities during this phase included:

- Requirement understanding
- Classification of System & Functional requirements
- Raising Clarifications
- Designing test cases
- Requirement tracking against TCs.
- LIBA Intern (preparing and submitting thesis for the completion of our EPGP-FSIA course).
- The thesis focuses on Study of Elderly in Old Age Home To study the profile of elderly residing in family settings and in old age homes. To study the awareness of elderly in the case of Pensions and Government Allowances and Schemes. To study and provide suggestions to improve the structure and facilities of the Old Age Homes.

AUGUST 2016 – JULY 2017 LIBA TRAINEE, MAVERIC SYSTEMS PVT.LTD.

- Financial Services and IT Assurance is a tailored 1-year course offered by Maveric in Loyola Institute of Business Administration training the filtered candidates in two verticals, Finance and Software Testing. The objective of the course is to gloom and nurture leaders in the field of Software Testing.
- The management vertical consists of subjects like Micro Economics, Marketing Management, Basics of Financial Accounting, Business & Research Methodology, Financial Markets.

- The subjects were handled by experienced faculty from LIBA for the course of 6 months and were assessed every three months once through assessments and mini research projects.
- Software Testing contains the following trainings and courses:
- Trained in API Testing-3 months (SOAP UI, Ready API).
- Trained in Automation Testing-3 months (HP-UFT).
- Domain-Underwent training in basics of Financial and Telecom Services.
- Scripting Languages-VB Script.
- Database- Fundamentals of Structured Query Language.
- SIT and UAT Manual Testing.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2017

EPGP-FINANCIAL SERVICES & IT ASSURANCE, LOYOLA INSTITUTE OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

2012 - 2016

B. TECH-INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, S.A ENGINEERING COLLEGE

CERTIFICATIONS/SKILLS

- Certified Scrum Master-Scrum Alliance
- ISTQB Certified Testing Professional-CTFL
- ISTQB Certified Test Professional-CTFL Agile Ext.
- Manual Testing
- Scrum Framework Implementation
- Domain Expertise-KYC, CDD, Credit Decisioning & Customer Onboarding in Retail Banking sector.

HONOURS & AWARDS

- Standard Chartered- RTOB Appreciation Award
 - Appreciated by the Head of Singapore during "RTOB Singapore Success Celebration" for my valuable contribution to successful project launch.
- Sports-Man Fee Waiver Scholarship (2011-2012)
 - Was awarded the Sports-Man Fee Waiver Scholarship during high school for winning the "Table Tennis Doubles Event" in State Level Bhartiyar Day Sports which was held at Vellore.
- Sports- Man Fee Refund Scholarship (2012-2013)
 - Scholarship was provided for winning prestigious tournaments which were conducted by the Anna University Board and other Inter-State tournaments.

• Winner @ Anna University Zonal Tournament (2012-2013 & 2014-2015)

- Zonal Winners of Anna University Zonal Tournaments in the category of Table Tennis for two consecutive years (2012-2013 & 2014-2015).

• Winner @ IIT Madras Sports Fest 2012

- Winner in the category of Table Tennis@ Sports Fest conducted by IIT Madras in the year, 2012.

• Third Place @ Tamil Nadu Inter Engineering Sports Meet

- Third Place in the category of Table Tennis, conducted by Aadhiyaman College on behalf of the Anna University Sports Board in the year 2013.